朋友:这到底是睡衣晚会还是葬礼啊?
Friend: Is this a pyjama party or a funeral?
开萝尔:得了吧,伙计们.
Carol: A pyjama party.Come on guys.
本:迈克,迈克!啊----!
Ben: Mike.Mike!Ahhhh!
迈克:嘘-----!
Mike: Shhhhh!
本:你又那样吓我,我要杀了你.
Ben: You scare me like that again, I'm going to slug you.
迈克:本,你说你能够胜任的,现在,如果你不...
Mike: Ben, you said you were up to this caper, now if you're not...
本:这蛇是我从斯汀金*萨利汶那儿买的,难道不是么?
Ben: I bought the snake from Stinky Sullivan, didn't I?
是我把它带回家的,难道不是么?
And I got it in the house, didn't I?
我还让爸爸,妈妈出去散散步.
I even got mum and dad to go for a walk.I've done everything.
所有事都是我干的,你什么事都没干.
You've done nothing.
迈克:错.听好了,
Mike: Wrong.Look.First, I'm the guy who thought of this plan.
首先,这主意是我想出来的;其次,
And second, I let you help me.Alright, now for the next step.
是我找的你来帮忙的.好了,现在下一步.
Ok now, do you remember what you are supposed to say when I run in there
你知不知道当我跑进来救那些女孩的时候,你应该说什么?
to rescue the girls?
本:好吧,小心点,迈克!塞西尔有毒.(注:"塞西尔",是本给蛇起的名字.)
Ben: Yeah.Be careful Mike!Cecil's poisonous.
迈克:没问题,没问题.别再管那蛇叫塞西尔了,好么?
Mike: Ok, ok.Don't call the snake Cecil.Right?
本:那是他的名字,他就叫这个.
Ben: That's his name.
迈克:本,它应该是条野蛇吧,野蛇是没有名字的.
Mike: Ben, It's supposed to be a wild snake.Wild snakes don't have names.
本:你怎么知道?
Ben: How do you know?
迈克:本.
Mike: Ben.
本:在脑子里想想,蛇到处都是,互相说"嗨,你好么"?
Ben: Think snakes go around calling each other 'Hey you'?
迈克:听着,我不在乎.咱们先说计划,好么?
Mike: Look.I don't care.Let's just get the plan straight.Alright?
杰森:计划!
Jason: The plan!
本:人们会怎么对我?
Ben: What are people trying to do to me?
麦琪:怎么回事?
Maggie: What's going on?
迈克:啊……没事.
Mike: Ah...Nothing.
奶奶:你!
Grandma: Yo!
本:奶奶.
Ben: Grandma.
杰森:嗨,这到底是怎么回事?
Jason: Hey, what's all this?
迈克:耶.
Mike: Yeah.
埃德:这么回事,我们刚巧在附近,
Ed: Well, we just happened to be in the neighborhood,
所以就想过来看看你们.
and we thought we'd drop in.
杰森:你们离家已经200英里了.
Jason: You're two hundred miles from home.
埃德:不,没那么远.这儿就是家.
Ed: No we aint.This is home.
奶奶:房子已经卖了.
Grandma: The house has been sold.
麦琪:什么,你们卖了自己的……
Maggie: What, you sold your ...
女孩们:啊--------------!
Girls: Ahhhhhhhhhhhhh!
本:塞西尔已经被他们发现了.
Ben: They've found Cecil.
女孩们:啊---!
Girls: Ahhh!
迈克:哇,哦!等会儿,女士们,问题会是什么啊?
Mike: Wow, wo!Wait now ladies.What seems to be the problem?
女孩:蛇!
Girl: Snake!
迈克:哦,不!
Mike: Oh no!
本:它可能在睡袋里,迈克.蛇喜欢温暖的地方.
Ben: It's probably in the sleeping bag Mike.They like warm places.
迈克:无所谓.现在,大家向后站.本,如果你受不了,就打911.(注:911,美国的报警电话,相当于我国的110)
Mike: Alright.Now stand back everybody.Ben, if I don't make it, call nine-one-one.
本:好舒服的一摸!
Ben: Nice touch!
开萝尔:等,我闻到有老鼠.
Carol: Wait a minute, I smell a rat.
女孩们:老鼠?啊---!
Girls: A rat?Ahhhh!
迈克:别担心.我去干掉它.
Mike: Don't worry.I'll get rid of it.
女孩们:啊--!
Girls: Ahh!
杰森:怎么回事这儿?你们都对斯汀金*萨利汶的蛇做了些什么?
Jason: What's going on here?What are you doing with Stinky Sullivan's snake?
开萝尔:对,那是我哥哥,迈克,
Carol: Yep, that's my brother.Crazy and funny Mike.
疯疯癫癫又有点可笑.请你们一定想个什么办法治一治迈克.他总是捉弄我,说出来都难以相信.
Would you guys please do something about Mike?
He's embarrassing me beyond belief.Ha ha, just right for the party night
奶奶:哦,开萝尔!
Grandma: Oh Carol!
开萝尔:奶奶!
Carol: Grandma!
奶奶:看,我的小乖孙女长得有多高了.
Grandma: Look how my little baby girl has grown up.
啊,你已经开始戴胸罩了?
Why, have you started wearing a bra?
开萝尔:妈妈,我没命了.
Carol: Mum, my life is over.
杰森:迈克,本,现在到厨房来.
Jason: Mike, Ben, in the kitchen now.
本:你太棒了,塞西尔.
Ben: You were great Cecil.
麦琪:妈妈,咱们到厨房里聊.
Maggie: Mum, let's talk in the kitchen.
奶奶:好吧,不管怎么说你还有个厨房.
Grandma: Well, at least you have a kitchen
开萝尔:别担心蛇,雪莉,蛇已经没了.
Carol: Don't worry about it Shelly.The snake has gone.
雪莉:不过,还有老鼠呢?
Shelly: well, what about the rat?
女孩们:老鼠!啊--!!!
Girls: The rat!Ahh!!!
杰森:现在,迈克.
Jason: Now Mike.We all agree.
我们一致同意,今晚客厅里除了开萝尔和她的朋友之外,谁都不许呆.
There's nobody in that living room tonight, except Carol and her friends.
迈克:得了,爸爸.你怎么能这样,单挑出我来?
Mike: Come on dad.How can you're picking on just me?
杰森:那是因为,我觉得本年龄还小,他肯定对这些还一无所知.
Jason: Well because I'm sure little Ben is an innocent party to all this.
本:啊哈哈哈.
Ben: Ah ha ha ha.
麦琪:本还有迈克,现在上楼睡觉.
Maggie: Ben and Mike, upstairs and in bed right now.
把你的蛇带上..
And take your reptile with you.
杰森:走那边.
Jason: That way.
迈克:没问题.不过,
Mike: Ok.Alright.But before we go,
在我们走之前,咱们搞搞清楚,具体都哪儿是禁区?
lets just clear up exactly what this off limits area includes.
杰森:去!
Jason: Go!
麦琪:那,妈妈,卖房子这件事,到底怎么回事?
Maggie: So mum, this business of selling the house.What's going on?
奶奶:现在我什么也不想说.
Grandma: Nothing I care to discuss right now.
杰森:我正想跟埃德聊.你知道,
Jason: I was just going out to talk to Ed.
我是多想跟埃德在一块.埃德!
You know how Ed and I love to pal around.Ed!
埃德:这个插哪儿?
Ed: Where can I plug this?
杰森:我看看.
Jason: Well,
麦琪:哪儿都行,爸爸.
Maggie: Anywhere daddy.
杰森:我刚出来看看你,埃德.
Jason: I was just coming out to see you Ed.
埃德:为什么?
Ed: Why?
麦琪:爸爸,他想看看你的房车.
Maggie: Daddy, he wants to see your trailer.
埃德:麦琪,那不是辆房车,而是辆1987年产的"漫步者"豪华车,发动机是"流浪者之梦".
Ed: Maggie, that is not a trailer.It's a nineteen eighty seven meanderer deluxe, the vagabonds dream machine.
杰森:"流浪者之梦"的机器.
Jason: The vagabonds dream machine.
埃德:对这个你也有了解?
Ed: You know about that?
杰森:哦,我看过它的广告.
Jason: Oh, I've seen the ad.
埃德:啊.或许你会喜欢出去亲自试一试?
Ed: Ah.Well, maybe you'd like to go outside and check it out?
或许你还可以帮我把它掉个方向?
Maybe you can help me turn it around.
杰森:好的,没问题.
Jason: Well alright.
麦琪:那,妈妈,到底是为了什么你们把自己的房子给卖了?
Maggie: So mum, why on earth did you sell your house?
奶奶:我觉得这事都怪你堂姐Effie.
Grandma: I blame it all on my cousin Effie.
麦琪:她都做了些什么?
Maggie: What did she do?
奶奶:她死了.
Grandma: She died.
麦琪:哦,我很难过.
Maggie: Oh I'm sorry.
奶奶:不管怎么,我都不是很喜欢她.
Grandma: I never liked her anyway.But I did go to her funeral.
不过,她的葬礼我还是去了.
I was only gone three days.
我只不过去了三天.可当我回到家的时候,
When I came back, your father had sold the house without even consulting me,
你父亲已经把房子给卖了,跟我都没说一声,
and bought that monstrosity out there,
然后就买了外面的那个怪物,他说要跟我在那里面共渡余生.
which he says we are going to spend the rest of our days in.
麦琪:不过,那听起来不像是爸爸的一贯做法.
Maggie: Well, that doesn't sound like daddy.
奶奶:哦,是,
Grandma: Oh yes it does.
他就是这样.自从我们从尼亚加拉大瀑布回来之后,他做事一直都很怪异.
He's been acting strangely ever since we went to Niagara Falls.
麦琪:你们什么时候去的尼亚加拉大瀑布?
Maggie: When did you go to Niagara Falls?
奶奶:在我们渡蜜月期间.
Grandma: On our honeymoon.
麦琪:妈妈,你告没告诉过爸爸你对所有这一切有多不开心?
Maggie: Mum, have you told daddy how unhappy you are about all of this?
奶奶:哦,我已经给他很多暗示了.
Grandma: Oh, I've given him plenty of hints.
我默默地坐着,眼睛盯着前方,目光茫然.
I sit still, staring straight ahead with a vacant look on my face.
麦琪:妈妈,你平常一直都目光茫然.
Maggie: Mum, you always have a vacant look on your face.
埃德:继续.
Ed: Go ahead.
杰森:哦,可以了.
Jason: Oh that's ok.
埃德:不,你自己亲眼看看.
Ed: No, see for yourself.
杰森:你的话我相信的.
Jason: I take your word for it.
埃德:你从来没有把我的话当真.
Ed: You never take my word for it.
杰森:好吧,咱们看一看.噢!
Jason: Ok, let's see.Ooh!
埃德:好么?
Ed: Well?
杰森:非常好.
Jason: Nice.
埃德:耶.而且,坚固耐用.
Ed: Yeah.And it's durable too.
杰森:的确,看得出.啊!
Jason: It is.I can tell.Oops!
埃德:啊!他他!
Ed: Ah!He he!
杰森:知道么,宣传册
Jason: You know, the brochures never do these things justice.
埃德:不,
Ed: No.Pres the round thing a me jig.
杰森:不,不用了.
Jason: No, that's alright.
埃德:按那东西……就是那个.
Ed: Press the darn...that's it.
杰森:很周到.
Jason: Sweet.
埃德:我想,如果这是我的城堡,
Ed: I figure, if this is going to be my castle,
那我应该有一个华贵的宝座.
I ought to have a decent throne.
杰森:在那儿我会很高兴的.
Jason: I could be happy in there.
埃德:听好了,在好莱坞,
Ed: Listen.Out in Hollywood, some of the stars use this, uh,
有些明星也用这个----"漫步者"豪华,作为他们的化妆间.
meanderer deluxe for their dressing rooms.
杰森:啊!是么!
Jason: Ah!
埃德:可不是,我想,
Ed: Uh hu.I figure, if it's good enough for Lony Anderson,
如果劳尼*安德森都觉得它很好,那对我一个退役的警察就没得说了.
its good enough for a retired cop.
杰森:真是一个令人难以置信的埃德.忘了劳尼*安德森跟您没法和比.
Jason: Well this is terrific Ed.Forget Lony Anderson.
埃德:我忘不了.
Ed: I can't.
杰森:哦.
Jason: Oh.Cowabunga!
埃德:你还挺有幽默感的么.
Ed: I didn't know you had a sense of humor.
Jason: You show me a man who's been married for seventeen years, I'll show you
a man with a sense of humor
埃德:你也会行的.
Ed: You know you're ok.
杰森:哦,看,船长的宝座!
Jason: Oh, look at that captain's chair!
埃德:想不想试试,看看大小如何?
Ed: Would you like to try it on for size?
杰森:我可以么?
Jason: Could I?
埃德:欢迎你成为我的客人.
Ed: Be my guest.
杰森:哦,好!哦,埃德!
Jason: Oh, right!Oh Ed!
埃德:哈?
Ed: Ha?
杰森:真让人眼红啊,埃德.
Jason: I envy you Ed.
埃德:你眼红我?
Ed: You envy me?
杰森:你在开玩笑?巡行在高速公路上,
Jason: You kidding?Cruising those highways,
每一天窗户外面的景致都不同;路在脚下延伸,没有尽头,
every day a different vista out of that window,
无边的风景,静静地等待你去尽情地探索.
tied to nothing but the open road and free to find adventure,
无忧无虑;没有一大堆病人天天等着你,
and follow wherever it leads.No responsibilities.
各式各样的问题,如果你偶尔忘了自己是位医生,
No patients waiting for you with problems that would just break your heart
不能一贯地保持职业所必需的与病人之间的距离,那么他们的那些问题也会让你的心灵饱受折磨.
if you didn't remind yourself constantly to keep your professional distance.
埃德:你到底在说什么?
Ed: What the hell are you talking about?
杰森:没事.知道么,
Jason: Nothing.You know,
当孩子长大成人以后,我也会这么做的.
when the kids grow up I would love to try something like this.
埃德:你也会?
Ed: You would?
杰森:啊呵.
Jason: Uh hu.
埃德:好!
Ed: Gee!
杰森:不过,我希望我能有您的那份勇气.
Jason: I just hope I have the courage to do what you did.
埃德:勇气?哇.杰森,
Ed: Courage?Wow.Boy!
这么些年来,我一直没有看错你,没有吧?
Jason, I haven't been wrong about you all these years, have I?
杰森:你叫我杰森.(注:直呼其名,埃德把杰森更多的是看作有共同志趣的伙伴,而不是长辈与晚辈间的关系.)
Jason: You called me Jason.
埃德:杰森不是你的名字么?
Ed: That is your name isn't it?
杰森:对.
Jason: Yeah.
麦琪:杰森!
Maggie: Jason!
杰森:在这儿呢,亲爱的.
Jason: In here honey.
埃德:玛格丽特*凯瑟琳,到这儿来,
Ed: Margaret Catherine.Come in here and see what your dear old dad had
看看你亲爱的老爸买了什么?
the courage to buy.
麦琪:你可以那么做.
Maggie: You can do it.
奶奶:不,我不可以.
Grandma: No I can't.
麦琪:不,你可以.
Maggie: Yes you can.
奶奶:不,我不可以.
Grandma: No I can't.
麦琪:杰森,我们得走了.
Maggie: Jason, we have to go.
埃德:杰森,我还想让你看件东西.
Ed: Jason, I want to show you something.
奶奶:这可以可拖一拖,麦琪.
Grandma: This can wait Maggie.
麦琪:不,这不能拖.他刚才叫你了么,杰森?
Maggie: No it can't.Did he just call you Jason?
埃德:杰森,每当我说"漫步者"的时候,
Ed: Jason, when I say the words 'meanderer deluxe',
现在我有的是一个什么的想法啊?
now what one feature comes to mind?
杰森:你没订购……
Jason: You didn't order the ...
埃德和杰森:水平控制箱!
Ed and Jason: custom cabin level control high box!
埃德:不过也没问题,把车停在10度的坡上,
Ed: There it is right here.
这种情况万中有一.
You never can tell when you're going to have to park on a ten degree angle.
奶奶:现在不合适,麦琪.
Grandma: This is not a good time Maggie.
埃德:40度,也没问题.
Ed: It can do a forty degree angle.
麦琪:哦,妈妈,现在太合适不过了.
Maggie: Oh mum.It's the perfect time.
杰森:嘿,麦琪,什么事?麦琪?
Jason: Ok Maggie.What is it?Maggie?
麦琪:就那而言,
Maggie: So with that, I told her that she owed it to herself,
我告诉我她了,
as well as daddy,
有她自己的原因,不过爸爸也有责任,
to tell him how she really felt about all this and for once stand up for
她应该告诉爸爸她对此事的真实感受并应该站出来扞卫自己的利益.
her rights.
杰森:麦琪,你这个建议太恐怖了.
Jason: Maggie, that was terrible advice.
麦琪:你不是也一直告诉我说,
Maggie: Aren't you always telling me how important it is to be truthful
夫妻之间彼此敞开心扉有多么多么的重要么?
with each other about our feelings?
杰森:亲爱的,对于我们俩是这样的,
Jason: Honey, that's for us.
可是你父母之间的婚姻从来没有建立在这种基础上.
Your parents' marriage has never been based on truth.
麦琪:那这样好么?
Maggie: That's a good thing?
杰森:他们这个样子,已经愉快地走过了37年的婚姻生活.
Jason: It's kept them happily married for thirty seven years.
奶奶:麦琪是对的.你是我见到的最顽固不化的男人,
Grandma: Maggie is right.You are the most pig headed man I have ever met.
你这个破铁罐子我再也不会踏进半步.
And I am not setting foot on this over blown tin can again.
埃德:没问题,我不在乎.
Ed: That's just fine.
今天晚上12点,开始从这儿走,
Come midnight tonight, I'm pulling out of here, with or without you.
来不来随你便.格洛里亚*斯汀布莱纳小姐.
And you can put that in your pipe and smoke it Miss Gloria Steinbrenner.
奶奶:麦琪,杰森,哪个是我的房间?
Grandma: Maggie, Jason, which room is mine?
奶奶:如果你相信一个男人,你会日渐后悔.男人,
Grandma: If you put your faith in any man, you'll live to regret it.
无一例外,到最后会变得脾气怪戾.你在听我说话?
All men go whacko eventually.You hear me?
开萝尔:哦,对.
Carol: Oh yeah.
麦琪:开萝尔,回去睡觉去.
Maggie: Carol, go back to your slumber party.
开萝尔:可是奶奶不放我们走.
Carol: Grandma won't let us.
杰森:没关系的.
Jason: It's ok.
麦琪:妈妈,你去给自己沏壶茶,杰森和我在开萝尔的房间里给您收拾张床.
Maggie: Mum, go ahead and make yourself a pot of tea and Jason and I will make up a bed for you in Carol's room.
奶奶:哦,别麻烦,我可以睡车库里.
Grandma: Oh don't go to any trouble.I can sleep in the garage.
麦琪:不行.来,杰森,我有句话跟你说.
Maggie: You will not.Come on Jason, I want to talk to you.
杰森:我有点怕.
Jason: I was afraid of that.
本:奶奶,嗨!
Ben: Grandma.Hi!
奶奶:本!
Grandma: Bennie!
本:跟你在一起,我们好高兴啊.
Ben: We have such a good time with you.
一块玩字谜,一块围着篝火唱歌.
Putting puzzles together, singing songs around the fire.
迈克:钢琴!我有没有听到有人提到钢琴啊?
Mike: Piano!Did I hear someone mention the piano?
奶奶:本刚才是说……
Grandma: Well Bennie was just saying...
迈克:奶奶,难道你还知道什么新曲儿么,啊?
Mike: Say grandma, you don't happen to know any new tunes, so ya?
奶奶:不过,说实话呢,
Grandma: Well as a matter of fact,
我刚刚买了本新的戴*斯特瑞茨的歌本.
I just bought the new Dire Straights song book.
本和迈克:哦-----!
Ben and Mike: Ohhh!
迈克:嗨,刚才本有没有提到说要给我们弹一曲钢琴啊?
Mike: Hey, did Bennie mention that we just got our piano tuned?
麦琪:杰森,你得劝劝他.
Maggie: Jason, you've got to talk some sense into him.
杰森:亲爱的,这是他俩的事,应该让他们自己想办法解决.
Jason: Honey, this is their business let them work it out.
麦琪:他们俩肯定不会想出任何办法的,很可能妈妈再也不跟爸爸说话了.
Maggie: Well they're not going to work anything out.Mum will probably never speak to dad again.
杰森:你是怎么知道的?
Jason: How do you know that?
麦琪:因为,
Maggie: Because if you ever did anything as stupid as expecting me to
如果你要是对我做出什么蠢事,比如想让我跟你住在个铁罐子里跟流浪汉似的,
live in a little tin thing like some hobo or something,
我肯定不会再跟你说话了.
I'd certainly never speak to you again.
杰森:真好,现在就知道答案了.
Jason: It's good to find out now.
(奶奶一边弹着钢琴一边唱着歌)
(Grandma playing piano and singing)
奶奶:看.
Grandma: Now look at them yo yo's.That's the way you do it.
你这该这么做,
You play the guitar on the MTV.
在MTV上弹吉它,爸爸不用上班,
Dad aint working, that's the way you do it,
你也应该这么做,
money for nothing and your chicks for free.
迈克:大家跳吧.
Mike: Everybody let's boogie.
杰森:嗨,迈克,多少次了……
Jason: Hey Mike, how many times...
迈克:嗨,爸爸,
Mike: Hey dad.We're just protecting the women folk here.
我们正在保护我们的女同胞.
You know especially since that giant prowlers been in the neighborhood,
尤其是最近以来附近地区有大盗出没,专偷少女的睡衣.
stealing the night gowns of teenage women.
女孩:啊---!
Girl: Ahhh!
杰森:埃德?
Jason: Ed?
埃德:哦,听着,
Ed: Oh.Look Jason, I was just starting to like you,
杰森,我刚刚对你有些好感,
so don't go saying something that's going to make me have no use for you
所以不要跟我说什么会让我觉得无用的话,好么?
again.Ok?
杰森:好的,可能花不了您多少时间,只是一个简短的谈话.
Jason: Well, this could be a short conversation.
埃德:很好.
Ed: Perfect.
杰森:埃德,你还是能在某些方面帮帮我的.
Jason: Ed, I could use your help.
埃德:车有问题了?
Ed: Car trouble?
杰森:不,是这样的,目前我有个问题就是,麦琪不很开心.
Jason: No, you see.Right now I'm having a problem keeping Maggie happy.
埃德:听着,谈性,我可受不了,免谈.
Ed: Hear, I won't put up with any of that sex talk.
杰森:不像你说的那样,埃德.
Jason: Nothing like that Ed.
直说吧,
It's just well, she asked me to come out here and tell you that this whole
她要我出来告诉你,您的这个什么在余生中周游各地的想法太……荒诞了.
idea of you spending the rest of your life traveling is...stupid.
不过我个人还是觉得这主意很不错.麦琪还让我转告您,
The problem is that I think it's fabulous.
说您现在这么对待凯特很不公平.我不知道这种说法我本人是不是赞同,
She also wanted me to tell you that you are treating Kate unfairly.
但是有一点我很明白,
Now I don't know if I agree with that or not,
我只是个外人,这是你们两人之间的事情.
but I do know its none of my business.
埃德:你这说得还没错.
Ed: Well you're right about that.
杰森:那,我去告诉麦琪说有关某些问题我们谈过了.
Jason: Well I have to go tell her that we talked about something.
埃德:比如什么问题?
Ed: Like what?
杰森:比如,
Jason: Well, like uh,
呃,如果麦琪说"不跟妈妈商量爸爸怎么可以这么做",
what am I supposed to say to her when she says "how come my dad did
那我该怎么跟她讲?
all this without consulting my mum'?
埃德:我为什么非得给她商量呢?
Ed: Why should I have to consult her?
杰森:是这样的,才能的,有些夫妻人家确实是互相商量着来的.
Jason: Well Ed, some married couple actually do talk to each other.
埃德:你是在说菲尔*道纳修(注:Phil Donahue,是美国电视谈话节目男主持人)和马龙*琥金斯,是不是?
Ed: If you are talking about that Phil Donahue and Marlon Perkins, aint ye?
杰森:不,埃德.你能不能先给我讲讲,你为什么突然卖掉自己的房子?
Jason: No Ed.Could you at least tell me why you suddenly sold your home?
埃德:为什么?我自己也不知道为什么.
Ed: Why?I don't know why.Maybe I ran out of chores.
也许,我可以从此摆脱家庭琐事的烦恼.我们有一个玫瑰花园,
We planted a rose garden, extended the back porch, painted.
后廊也扩了,描绘了,我退休六个月,
I did those things the first six months I was on retirement.I don't know why.
做的就是这些.我自己也说不清楚为什么.
Just recently the leg broke off my old easy chair because I was spending
只是在最近,我那把旧的安乐椅腿折了,
so much time sitting in it, watching that wheel of fortune.
因为我坐的时间太久了,不过这也没有什么不好.也或许是因为上个月,
Which is not a half bad show, by the way.
房贷我们全部付清了,前后25年,一次也有拖欠过.
Maybe it's because last month we paid the house off.
为了以示庆贺,我们回到名符其实的自己的家里,
After twenty five years and not missing a single payment.
倒头大睡.为什么会这样,
And to celebrate, we went home and fell asleep.I don't why.
我也不知道.我问你个问题,你觉得你自己还能活几年?
Let me ask you something.How many years do you figure you've got left?
杰森:这我还没想过太多.
Jason: I haven't thought about it much.
埃德:我想过,很多.
Ed: I do.A lot.
杰森:我能理解.
Jason: I understand.
埃德:你真能理解?
Ed: You do?
杰森:对.
Jason: Yeah.
埃德:哦,如果我妻子也能理解就好了.
Ed: Oh, I wish my wife did.
杰森:那,你有没有试着把自己的真实感受跟她讲一讲?
Jason: Well have you tried telling her how you feel.
埃德:听好了,如果她想嫁给沟通大师,
Ed: look, if she wanted to marry a communicator,
she should have married Walter Cronkite.She'll change her mind.Won't she
奶奶:他自己会改变主意的,难道他不会么?
Grandma: He'll change his mind.Won't he?
麦琪:会的,他肯定会的,妈妈.他是个敏感,细腻,体贴的人,是个讲奉献不求回报的人.
Maggie: Sure he will mum.He's a sensitive, giving human being.
奶奶:他是头公驴,死犟死犟.
Grandma: He's a jack arse.
麦琪:他就是.
Maggie: You're right.
奶奶:麦琪,他可是你父亲.
Grandma: Maggie, he's your father.
麦琪:对不起.
Maggie: Sorry.
奶奶:我自己该做些什么?
Grandma: What will I do with myself?
麦琪:哦,妈妈,我觉得,一切肯定都会向最好方向发展的.
Maggie: Oh mum, I'm sure everything will work out for the best.
奶奶:我知道.我会照你的样子去做,重新开始我的生活.
Grandma: I know.I'll do what you did.Resume my career.
麦琪:妈妈,在二战期间您做过铆工.
Maggie: Mum, you were a riveter during world war two.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,你那边情况怎么样?
Maggie: Oh honey, how did it go?
杰森:情况怎么样?哦,情况很好,
Jason: How did it go?Oh it went well.Actually I think it went very well.
实际上,应该说非常好.确实非常好.
Very well indeed.
奶奶:埃德!
Grandma: Eddie!
麦琪:爸爸!爸爸!
Maggie: Daddy!Daddy!This has gone far eno.
埃德:这跟你没关系,玛格丽特*凯瑟琳.
Ed: This is no business of yours Margaret Catherine.
你有什么要说的么,凯特?
Do you have anything to say Kate?
奶奶:没.你有什么要……
Grandma: No.Do you have anything to
埃德:没,一个字儿也没.
Ed: Not a word.
奶奶:那好,没关系.
Grandma: Alright then.
麦琪:别生气,妈妈.如果你不愿意自己说呢,那我来替您说两句.
Maggie: Hold it mum.Now if you're not going to speak for yourself, t hen I am going to speak for you.
杰森:麦琪,你怎么能代替别人呢.
Jason: Maggie, you shouldn't speak for somebody else.
麦琪:是这样的,某些人以后肯定会和这个老头现在一样疯疯癫癫的.
Maggie: Well someone sure has to with the screwy way this man is behaving.
杰森:你父亲没有干什么疯疯癫癫的事啊.
Jason: Your father hasn't done anything screwy.
麦琪:得了,杰森.
Maggie: Come on Jason.
居然有这念头,剩下这半辈子要和老婆在这个罐子里面过.
Just the whole idea of spending the rest of their lives in this thing.
看,就在那儿.
It's way out there.
杰森:麦琪,对一部分人而言,这可以是一种梦想.有许许多多有头脑的,
Jason: Maggie, this happens to be a dream for some people.
事业有成的人,-----我可以这么说么,埃德?
A lot of intelligent responsible people, I might Ed.
麦琪:那好吧,比方说谁?
Maggie: Well, name one?
杰森:我.我就想退休之后这么过.
Jason: Me.I'd love to spend the rest of my days like this.
麦琪:你脑子里进什么了,啊?你怎么就跟房子过不去了?
Maggie: What is it with you men?What do you have against houses?
杰森:好了,你父亲可能一时冲动,
Jason: Alright, your father might have been acting a little impulsively,
做得有点鲁莽,不过,
but he was a desperate man.
他曾有过绝望无助的时候,没有什么可以指望,
He had nothing to look forward to except 'wheel of fortune'.
只有听凭"命运车轮"的安排.当然这也不是完全不好.
Which is not a half bad show.
麦琪:那,他怎么不告诉妈妈呢?
Maggie: Well then why didn't he tell mum that?
杰森:因为他脾气不是那样.
Jason: Because that is not his style.
麦琪:那,他的脾气是臭脾气.
Maggie: Well his style stinks.
杰森:不过,37年了,他的脾气
Jason: His style was fine for thirty seven years.
奶奶:38年.
Grandma: Thirty eight.
麦琪:您介意么,妈妈?我们大家在这儿讨论这个问题.
Maggie: Do you mind mum?We are having a discussion here.
埃德:玛格丽特*凯瑟琳,不准对你妈妈那个样子说话.
Ed: Margaret Catherine, I will not have you talking to your mother that way.
麦琪:好吧,爸爸,再怎么着我跟妈妈说话,不像某些人有话不说独断专行.
Maggie: Well dad.At least I talk to her.
埃德:我能跟你妈妈好商好量,不比其它人差.
Ed: I can talk to your mother as well as anyone can.Kate, I'm sorry.
凯特,对不起,我应该早些时候告诉你一声我打算要卖房子.
I should have told you I was selling the house.
麦琪:听到了么?他说的是"告诉",自己拿了主意然后通知你一声,不是真的要征求别人意见.
Maggie: See.He said told instead of asked.
奶奶:埃德,我不知道你在家里是如此的不开心.
Grandma: Eddie, I didn't know you were so unhappy at home.
埃德:你知道我不会抱怨.
Ed: Well you know I don't complain much.
你看,这个房子还没有签约.
Look, the house hasn't gone through escrow yet.
我可以拿回我们的钱.
I can take this thing back to Smiling Jakes Rv and get our money back.
奶奶:埃德,你要想知道我要做什么么?
Grandma: Eddie, are you asking me what I want to do?
埃德:有点想,对,我想知道.
Ed: Well, kinda, yeah.
奶奶:那好,能让你开心的,
Grandma: Well, what would make you happy is what would make me happy.
都能让我开心.我们现在傻站在这儿干么呢?外面有一个精彩的世界可以看.
What are we standing out here for?There's a whole big world out there to see.
埃德:你说得很对,凯特.
Ed: You're right about that Kate.
麦琪,能不能代我们向孩子们道个别?对了,
Maggie, will you tell the kids we said goodbye?
和你的一席谈话,的确是非常非常受用.
And it sure was nice talking to you, oh uh oh.....
杰森:杰森.
Jason: Jason.
埃德:对.
Ed: Right.
麦琪:妈妈,你的行李箱怎么办?
Maggie: Mum, what about your suitcase?
奶奶:寄给我吧.让费城投递中心.
Grandma: Send it to me.In care of general delivery Philadelphia.
埃德:凯特,我想,是不是我们应该重返尼亚加拉大瀑布.如果你同意的话?
Ed: Kate, I was thinking we should go back to Niagara Falls.If it's ok?
奶奶:不是同意,而是非常同意.麦琪,别担心,我自己的衣服,用不着了.
Grandma: It's better than ok.Maggie, never mind.I won't be needing my clothes.
麦琪:哦,杰森,真的是很美好的一件事情诶!
Maggie: Oh Jason.Isn't it wonderful?
杰森:对.
Jason: Yeah.
麦琪:你刚才喷的都是些鬼话,你不会真的喜欢住在那样的罐子里吧?
Maggie: All that boloney you were spouting,
你在糊弄人.
how you'd really like to live like that, did the trick.
杰森:可不是,我是专家.
Jason: Well, I am a professional.
女孩:啊---!
Girls: Ahhhh!
迈克和本:(模仿鬼怪的声音)
Mike and Ben: (making monster noises)
本:嗨,妈妈,嗨,爸爸,别害怕,是我.
Ben: Hi mum, hi dad.No worries, it's just me.
女孩:这边来,迈克.(耳语)起作用了.他在学我.
Girl: This way mike.(Whispers) It worked.He's following me.
迈克:你在哪?
Mike: Where are you?
女孩:在这儿呢,迈克.不,迈克,我说了,是这儿.
Girl: Over here Mike.No Mike, I said over here.
迈克:你在哪儿呢?我看不到你们.
(女孩们用刮脸泡沫对迈克突然袭击)
00:23:00,600
Mike: Where are you?I can't see you guys. (Girls attack him with shaving foam)